(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-08T02:21:10.330914",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Ina'nis.
She spent her days singing by the lake.
But one day,
She woke up somewhere else.
透き通る季節が過ぎ
The crystal-clear season has passed,
風がまた熱を連れてくる
The wind brings the heat back once again.
何千回も巡って
Passing by thousands of times,
何万回も輝く
Shining tens of thousands of times,
そうやって光が生まれる
That is how the light is born.
日差しが溶けてる
The sunlight is melting,
空の向こう
Beyond the sky,
どこまでも透明な青
Into an endlessly transparent blue.
スピードを上げた
I accelerated...
想いたち
My thoughts,
自分の意志で
with my own will,
今飛び立つの
now I take flight.
感じている
I can feel
無邪気な誓い
an innocent vow.
言葉は知らない
Though I do not know the words,
流れていく
letting myself flow
水の行くえに
to where the water leads,
心を馳せよう
I will let my thoughts wander.
透きとおる季節が過ぎ
As the transparent season passes by,
風がまた熱を連れてくる
the wind brings the warmth back once more.
傷あとは消えていったわ
The scars have all faded away,
あふれだす情熱のシンフォニー
into an overflowing symphony of passion.
何千回も巡って
Orbiting thousands of times,
何万回も輝く
shining tens of thousands of times,
育っていく光が生まれる
a growing light is born.
忘れじの言の葉
[Title: The Unforgotten Words]
言の葉を紡いで
Spinning words together,
微睡んだ唄かた
a slumbering, ephemeral song.
旅人 迷い込む
A traveler wanders in,
御伽の深い霧
into the deep mist of a fairy tale.
差し伸べた手のひら
An outstretched palm,
そっと触れる予感
a premonition of a gentle touch.
受け止めて零れた
Caught as they spilled,
光の愛し雫
beloved droplets of light.
ルア・リ・ティ・ア　ルア・リ・ティ・ア
Rua li tia, rua li tia...
面影 移ろって
The remnants of the past shift,
追憶の幻
a phantom of memories.
想いの果てる場所
The place where feelings come to an end
まだ遥か遠くて
is still so far away.
求め探して彷徨ってやがて唄われて
Seeking, searching, wandering, and eventually being sung,
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
it becomes thousands, millions, billions of melodies.
いつか失い奪われて消える運命でも
Even if it is destined to someday be lost, stolen, and vanish,
それは忘れられることなく紡がれる物語
it is a story that will never be forgotten and will continue to be spun.
指先を絡めて
Intertwining fingertips,
触れる誰かの夢
touching someone's dream.
刻まれた想いの
Of the feelings etched deep,
木霊だけが響く
only the echoes resonate.
言の葉を紡いで
Spinning words together,
微睡んだ唄かた
a slumbering, ephemeral song.
旅人の名前を
A traveler's name
おとぎ話という
they call a fairy tale.
求め探して彷徨ってやがて路となり
Seeking, searching, wandering, and eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, millions, billions of heroes march on.
いつか失い奪われて消える運命でも
Even if it is destined to someday be lost, stolen, and vanish,
それは忘れられることなくここにある
it will never be forgotten and will remain right here.
求め探して
Seeking, searching...
彷徨うて やがて倒れて
Wandering, and eventually collapsing...
幾千の砂に 砂の旋律となる
They become thousands of sands, a melody of sand.
いつか失い 奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it is destined to be lost, stolen, and vanished one day...
それは 忘れられることなき 物語
That is a story that will never be forgotten.
ルルールルルルルールールルールルルルールー
Lu lu lu...
君の中にある 赤と青き線
The red and blue lines inside of you...
それらが結ばれるのは 心の臓
They connect at your heart.
風の中でも 負けないような声で
With a voice that won't lose to the wind...
届ける言葉を 今は育ててる
I am nurturing the words to deliver to you.
時はまくらぎ
Time is a crosstie,
風はにきはだ
the wind is soft skin,
星はうぶすな
the stars are the guardian deities,
人はかげろう
and people are like a shimmer.
なんで泣いてるのと聞かれ答えれる
When asked why I'm crying, I can answer...
涙なんかじゃ
It's not just tears...
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで 追いつかない
They are nowhere near enough to explain the meaning of our meeting.
この身ひとつじゃ 足りない叫び
With just this one body, my cries are not enough.
君の手触れた時にだけ震えた
Only when I touched your hand, it trembled...
心があったよ
I realized I had a heart.
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り
How many meanings must we cross over...
つけるのかな
before we can finally reach each other?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
Even if it's foolishness, even if it's ugliness...
正しさのその先で
Beyond what is deemed right...
君と手を取りたい
I want to take your hand.
思い出せない 大切な記憶
I cannot remember that precious memory...
言葉にならない ここにある想い
These feelings inside me cannot be put into words.
もしかしたら
Could it be...
それだけでこの心はできている
that my heart is made of nothing but that?
もしかしたら
Could it be...
君に気づいてと今もその胸を
that even now, it is beating in your chest...
打ち鳴らす
asking you to notice?
なんで泣いてるのと聞かれ答えれる
When asked why I'm crying, I can answer...
涙なんかじゃ
It's not just tears...
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで 追いつかない
They are nowhere near enough to explain the meaning of our meeting.
この身ひとつじゃ 足りない叫び
With just this one body, my cries are not enough.
君の手触れた時にだけ震えた
Only when I touched your hand, it trembled...
心があったよ
I realized I had a heart.
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り
How many meanings must we cross over...
つけるのかな
before we can finally reach each other?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
Even if it's foolishness, even if it's ugliness...
正しさのその先で
Beyond what is deemed right...
...beyond correctness,
君と生きてきたい
I wanted to live with you.
Wow...
Hello, everyone!
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
How are you guys doing?
Good? Good. Are we all miraculously preser—
I can't talk. Are we all miraculously preserved?
Yay! I can hear you guys. Yay, yay, Ina, wah, wah!
Hi! Good to see you guys.
Welcome to my birthday live! We made it in time this year! Let's go!
And of course, don't forget to, you know, talk about it, take screenshots,
And of course, don't forget to talk about it, take screenshots,
you know, share it with everyone, using the hashtag...
and share it with everyone using the hashtag...
...over here!
Yeah! So that I can also, you know, read what you guys have thought about while watching the stream and stuff.
Yeah! So that I can also read what you guys thought about while watching the stream.
And, yeah! Of course, you know, let's talk about... where are we? Where are we?
And, yeah! Of course, let's talk about... where are we? Where are we?
I just went through a door and suddenly we ended up in this...
I don't know, it almost looks like we're inside a storybook or something.
I have no idea where we are. But you know what? We're gonna roll with it, because that's all we do.
I have no idea where we are, but we're gonna roll with it, because that's what we do.
And, of course, let us not forget... my clothes also changed! Look!
And, of course, let's not forget... my clothes also changed! Look!
Do I look cute?
Oh, ta-da-da~
Wow! And of course, you know, look at all the details! My... my flaps have gotten longer?
Wow! And look at all the details! My flaps have gotten longer?
Um, I have this cool gauntlet now. Look at this.
I have this cool gauntlet now. Look at this.
Wow! I feel like a knight.
I feel like I can defeat all evil.
And of course, I got my... I don't know, three glass pens behind me?
And of course, I have three glass pens behind me.
Wow! I wonder if this is my weapon.
Can poke people with my glass pens.
I can poke people with my glass pens.
And all the details on the dress. Isn't it beautiful?
And look, my skirt is actually made out of Takodachis.
Ooh! That's right.
And also I can already see it, you know, you guys are going, "Oh, Ina, that's me, that's me."
And I can already see you guys going, "Oh, Ina, that's me, that's me!"
But yeah, look at this beautiful, beautiful outfit.
Um, of course, I got to thank Kuroboshi-papa for designing this wonderful, wonderful outfit.
Of course, I have to thank Kuroboshi-papa for designing this wonderful outfit.
Thank you, Kuroboshi-papa!
You're always the, the, the best, best at making the outfits. So, yeah.
You're always the absolute best at making outfits. So, yeah.
And you know, I want to talk about a lot of things, but it is my birthday, and I'm going to go have fun around here.
I want to talk about a lot of things, but it is my birthday, so I'm going to go have fun around here.
I don't know where we are, but, you know, I'm going to go look around and see where we end up. We'll see, I don't know.
I don't know where we are, but I'm going to look around and see where we end up.
Maybe we'll find something fun to do, but...
...yeah, you know, I guess I'll see you guys around. Take care!
...yeah, I guess I'll see you guys around. Take care!
What is this place? I don't know. Do they have food around here?
Hmm.
お、え、お、え？
Oh, eh? Oh, eh?
あ、アキ先輩じゃないですか！
Ah, isn't that Aki-senpai?!
お、イナ！イナ！アキ先輩！
Oh, Ina! Ina! Aki-senpai!
え？何で石になってたんですか？
Why were you turned into stone?
分からないです...
I don't know...
なんか、なんか、もう一個影があったような気がして、気づいたら... あ、影が！
I felt like there was another shadow, and then before I knew it... Ah, a shadow!
待ってたけど...
I was waiting, but...
イナ！ここどこ？私も知らないです。
Ina! Where is this? I don't know either.
イナも知らない？はい。
You don't know either, Ina? Right.
なんか急に、なんかドアに入りとしたら、衣装もこれになったし、ここどこだろう、って...
Suddenly, after I went through a door, my outfit changed to this, and I was wondering where we were...
イナ、可愛い！
Ina, you look so cute!
あ、新衣装！可愛い！そう、そうなんです、可愛いでしょ！
Ah, my new outfit! So cute! Yes, exactly! Isn't it cute?
めっちゃ可愛い！
It's so cute!
くるっとして、くるっとして！可愛い、可愛い！
Spin around, spin around! Cute, cute!
いや、でもここ、なんか全然知らない場所でアキ先輩がいて、なんか嬉しい！本当？そう？
But still, finding you here in this completely strange place makes me so happy! Really? Is that so?
え、アキちゃんもこの3Dの姿でイナとこうやって会えてるの、実は嬉しい！
Actually, I'm really happy to be able to meet you like this in 3D too!
嬉しい！実は私、あの、アキ先輩といつか、あの、歌ったり踊ったりやりたかったんです...
I'm so happy! Actually, I've always wanted to sing and dance with you, Aki-senpai...
あ、いいですか？
Oh, is it okay?
え？じゃあ、もしかして、一緒に今日は歌えるの？
Eh? Then, does that mean we can sing together today?
いいんですか？
Is it really okay?
はい、歌いましょう！やったー！嬉しい！
Yes, let's sing! Yay! I'm so happy!
じゃあ、どの曲がいいかな？
Then, which song should we do?
ふむふむ。ホロライブの曲もあるしね、色々。
Hmm. There are various Hololive songs too.
そうですね。でも、先輩の曲の中で、一番好きな曲はやっぱりあの曲ですね。
That's true. But, among Senpai's songs, my favorite is definitely that one.
え、あれ？あれですね。
Eh? That one? It is, right?
でも、分かんないから言ってくれないと。
But you have to tell me, or I won't know.
あれですね。アキ先輩がこう、あ、あ、あれ。ちょっとセクシーな...
It's that one. Where Aki-senpai does that... slightly sexy...
セクシーダンス？セクシーダンスはいっぱいある？
Sexy dance? There are a lot of sexy dances?
あ、いっぱいじゃないか。
Ah, wait, maybe not a lot.
でも、でも、アキ先輩だったら、この曲ですね。
But when it comes to Aki-senpai, it has to be this song.
じゃあ、今日は一緒に「シャルイース」、いいんですか？歌おう、イナ！
Then, today, together, "Shalleis"... is it really okay? Let's sing it, Ina!
はい、よろしくお願いします！嬉しい！
Yes! I look forward to it! I'm so happy!
嬉しい！シャルイース。
I'm so glad! Shalleis.
イナとこうやって歌うのもね、初めてだよね。
Singing together with Ina like this is a first, isn't it?
そうですね。なんかライブとかあんまり機会がなくて。
That's true. Since we didn't have many chances to perform live together.
やっと、やっと、やっと！嬉しい、嬉しい！
Finally, finally, finally! I'm so happy, so happy!
じゃ、じゃあ、アキロゼの「シャルイース」は、何と言っても...
Then, Akirose's "Shalleis" is, after all...
アキロゼの国の伝承歌。
a legendary song of Akirose's country.
だから、何かね、イナの助けになることが、あるかもしれないし。
So, maybe it could be of some help to Ina somehow.
一緒に歌って、パワーをね、つけてもらいたいなと思うから。
I want us to sing together and give you strength.
頑張ろう！
Let's do our best!
はい、じゃ、よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Well then, let's do this!
ドキドキする！行きましょうか。
My heart is racing! Shall we go?
あ、こっちこっちこっち、こっち、あ、こっちこっち。
Ah, this way, this way, this way...
よし、じゃ、頑張るぞ！はい。
Alright, let's do our best! Yes.
コンタス ハレリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareliya on shalleis
アルミタポ ミイ ジリーク
Armitapo miy jilik
セクラクス オクノクラス ディノ ケティン
Sekuraks oknokras dino ketin
ハプワ ミュキール シャル ベール
Hapuwa myukiiru sharu beeru
ヤ イイディリィ レオ ミイ ダセク チュー
Ya iydiliy leo miy daseq chuu
テゲイダベイ ミイ ダス リーカ リヤ
Tegeydavey miy dasu riika liyah
ネッシィ ディーナス ウェナベティカス
Nessy diinas wenavetikas
ティミィ ホラース モロ フワ アプワ
Teemiy horaas molo fuwa apuwa
コンタス ハレリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareliya on shalleis
アルミタポ ミイ ジリーク
Armitapo miy jilik
アルヤ トールストゥ リヤ
Aluya toorustu liyah
ノント キヤストゥ リヤ
Nonto kiyastuu liyah
コンタス ハレリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareliya on shalleis
アルミタポ ミイ ジリーク
Armitapo miy jilik
セクラクス オクノクラス ディノ ケティン
Sekuraks oknokras dino ketin
ハプワ ミュキール シャル ベール
Hapuwa myukiiru sharu beeru
エ トゥラーリラーリビリヤ
E tulaarilaaribiliya
パラトス トルミヤ ティスロモール
Paratos torumiya tislomor
クルソウィニヤ ミナイチュリック
Kurusowiniya minaichurik
メネラスト ムウォクルル
Meneerast muwokurur
ティリラル ピプル ノトムル
Teeriraalu piipuuru notomuru
ファルマイ ビラレマ ムセリフリ
Farumai birarema muselifuri
オノマドール ワミロー
Onomador wamiro
ウンダルーネ
Uundarune
ティナウィヤ サラメ
Tinawiiya sarame
テカント ミラリラ ア
Tekanto miralira ah
シャルイース
[Sharlice]
アルヴィス・ラ・シーミヤ
Alvess la simia
ヴィーモラ・シェロ・ニ・コーニャ
Vimora shelo ni konia
イミ・ヴォイ・プロポネーラ
Imi voi proponela
ヴィーモラ・シェロ・ラ
Vimora shelo la
コントス・アッレリヤ・オ・シャルイース
Kontos alleluiah o' Sharlice
アミミ・タ・ポキ・マイ・ツリ
Amimi ta poki mai tuli
イクソス・オクノ・クラスティナ・ケティン
Ixsos okno crestina ketin
アヴォラミュ・キルス・シャル・ヴリール
Avolamyu kirus charu vril
マリュ・フェセ・アムト
Maryu fese amto
モーラ・フェ・カント
Mora fe kanto
イミリ・オイ・ヤシュ・モーロ・フォー・ラー
Imiri oi yash moro fo la
イミリ・オイ・ヤシュ・モーロ・フー・ハッ・プー・アー
Imiri oi yash moro fu ha pu ah
クロイウタ
[Kroiuta]
あたらセリ
Such a pity...
破滅　合うた
...we met with ruin.
獣と成り　ときり
Becoming beasts, cut away...
奪い去る　張りの調べ
A tense melody that snatches all away...
輪廻の　ひとたり
A single drop of samsara...
千度羽ばたく雨
The rain that flutters a thousand times...
濃い暗い白から
From the deep, dark white...
いつ終わると口聞き
Speaking of when it will end...
声甘い黄色奪ね
Snatched away by a sweet, yellow voice...
ささめく
Whispering...
黒い花
Black flower...
あの声が
That voice...
壊れた目の
Of broken eyes...
ある
Exists...
もも
A hundredfold...
黒い花
Black flower...
あの歌が
That song...
つくりまい
The dance of creation...
いつ
When...
ある
Exists...
もも
A hundredfold...
いみ
Meaning...
アトラスリー
Atorasuree...
コウリアウタ
Kouria uta...
アクム ナマウ
Akumu namau...
ヒオウ
Hiou...
ウトウ タチシルシガ
Utou tachishirushi ga...
イク アカイモリカラ
Iku akai mori kara...
イヌベクケガレアラムヨワイアノ
Inubeku kegare aramuyowai ano...
ホモイ
Homoi...
ナガレル
Nagareru...
クロアイハナ
A black flower...
アノコエガ
that voice...
イノリノチガ
the blood of prayer...
アルママ
just as it is...
クロイハナ
A black flower...
アノウタガ
that song...
ザンゲノヒガ
the day of confession...
アルママ
just as it is...
キエ
fading away...
サイアクハ
Disaster...
マチオリル
descends upon the town...
コワレタ トキ
A broken time...
ヒト
People...
ユメ
Dreams...
クリカエリ
Repeating...
ワカレユキ
Parting ways...
ユルサレ サル
Forgiven, departing...
オト
Sounds...
ハナ
Flowers...
シウ
fading...
秘密の黄昏に君の手を取った
In the secret twilight, I took your hand.
古のバラード繰り返すように
As if repeating an ancient ballad,
紡ぐ
we spin it.
no va e sa ra...
君のことをいつも歌いたい
I want to always sing of you.
哀しい夜もぬくもりで満たして
Filling even the sad nights with warmth.
愛を見つけて
Find love...
ひな菊が咲いてた 白い月輝いてた
Daisies were blooming, the white moon was shining.
君の囁きで始まるよ 永遠の
With your whisper, eternity begins...
storia...
水の中
In the water,
沈んでいった
sinking down...
懐かしい
A nostalgic
恋の物語
love story.
光と影の中から
From the light and shadow,
愛しさは生まれて
affection is born,
還る
and returns.
君の目を見てた
I was looking into your eyes.
その腕の中で
Within those arms,
恋人のささやき
whispers of lovers,
星屑のちった
scattered stardust.
いにしえのバラード
An ancient ballad,
泉を満たして
filling the spring,
風は西へ
the wind goes west.
やさしい歌を
I want to sing
君と歌いたい
a gentle song with you.
五月の月が
The May moon
今ここにある
is right here now.
恋の歌が
Because a love song
今宵響くから
will echo tonight,
冷たい胸を
fill a cold chest
ぬくもりで満たして
with warmth.
語ろう
Let's tell
愛の storia
the storia of love.
あれ？
Huh?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫？大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay? Are you alright?
あれ？動ける！
Huh? I can move!
動ける！
I can move!
We can move!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
動けるってなったね！いつものやつだ
We're able to move now! It's the usual thing.
イナちゃんが助けてくれたやつ？
Is this what Ina-chan saved us with?
なんか、なんか、ぴょんしたら動けるようになった
Somehow, when I jumped, we were able to move again!
嬉しい！よかった！ありがとう！
I'm so glad! Thank goodness! Thank you!
何で石になってたんですか？
Why were we turned into stone?
何でだっけ？
Why was that again?
なんかね、なんか見たよね？なんかいたんだよな
Well, we saw something, right? There was something there.
翼が...
Wings...
なんかね
Yeah...
竜っぽかったかな？
Was it dragon-like?
竜？あ、ドラゴン？
A dragon? Ah, a dragon?
ドラゴン？竜っぽかった気がするけど
A dragon? I feel like it was dragon-like, but...
わかんない！
I don't know!
わかんないね！覚えてない！
We don't know! We don't remember!
あ、そういえば！そういえばイナちゃん！
Ah, by the way! Speaking of which, Ina-chan!
あなた、お誕生日じゃない？
Isn't it your birthday?
おめでとうございます！お誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
いや、大好きな二人と一緒って嬉しい！
I'm so happy to be with two of my favorite people!
照れちゃう！嬉しい！
We're blushing! So happy!
なんかイナちゃんとね、5期生はね、デビュー日近かったもんね
You know, Ina-chan and the 5th gen debuted around the same time.
そう、1ヶ月くらいだったから
Yes, it was about a month apart.
なんかもう同期みたいな
So we're almost like genmates!
えー、いいな！嬉しい！
Aww, that's so nice! I'm so glad!
でも、ししろんと中々歌う機会があまりなくて
But I rarely had the chance to sing with Shishiron.
いつかトワ先輩とししろんと歌いたいなって...
I've been wanting to sing with Towa-senpai and Shishiron someday...
えー、嬉しい！
Aww, we're so glad!
二人の歌声が大大大大好きなので嬉しいです！
I love your singing voices so, so, so much, so I'm really happy!
ありがとう！私たちも大大大大好きだよ！
Thank you! We love you so, so, so much too!
え、私も好きだから！
Hey, I love you too!
いやいや、わための方が好き！
No, no, Watame loves her more!
ししろんの方が好きだから！わための方が好き！
Shishiron loves her more! / Watame loves her more!
が好きなの？
...do you like?
いやいや。
No, no.
二人... 助け... 助けて。
You two... Help... Help me!
あれ？でもイナちゃん、なんか服が可愛くなってる。
Huh? But Ina-chan, your outfit got so cute.
ね、なんか！
Right? It did!
なんかドアがあって、ドアをピョンとしたら、この衣装になりました。
There was a door, and when I jumped through, I ended up in this outfit!
ええ！可愛い！
Wow! It's so cute!
似合ってる！
It suits you so well!
よく見たらさ、タコダチ...
If you look closely, there are Takodachis...
あ、ね！タコダチいっぱいいるんですよ、これ。
Ah, right! There are so many Takodachis on it.
いっぱいおるよな、タコダチ。
There are indeed a lot of Takodachis.
靴も！靴もタコダチ。
Even the shoes! The shoes are Takodachis too.
あ、本当だ。タコダチおる。可愛くない？
Ah, you're right! There are Takodachis. Isn't that cute?
おしゃれだね。
It's very stylish.
いや、でも、嬉しい。
But still, I'm so happy.
この... うう、嬉しい！
This... Ooh, I'm so happy!
うれしい！こちらこそだよ。
We're happy too! The pleasure is ours.
あ、でも、え？あなた、ちょっと、時間があるんじゃないの？
Oh, but wait... don't you have a schedule to keep?
え？もう時間？あ、やばいやばい。
Eh? Is it time already? Oh no, oh no.
は！もう行かなきゃかも。
Oh! I think I have to go now.
ハバライブの収録、あなたあるんじゃないの？
Don't you have that "HabaLive" recording session?
やばいやばい、飛行機乗らなきゃ！
Oh no, oh no! I have to catch a flight!
ちょっと飛行機乗って。行かなきゃだから、行こう、行こう。
Hurry and catch your flight. Since you have to go, let's head out.
じゃあ、またあとでね！ありがとう！バイバイ！
Well, see you later then! Thank you! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！急げ、急げ！
Bye-bye! Hurry, hurry!
Ah, that was so fun! Oooh, I got to finally sing with Shishiron, and of course with Watame-senpai.
I'm so, so happy, you know? Huh, they did say they saw something like a dragon, a dragon?
Well... after all this singing and dancing, I'm kind of... kind of getting sleepy, so I'm just...
Just going to take a... small nap, okay? I'm going to take a small nap, so... Okay. Yeah, I'll just go... go...
(Inja kohne ba...)
(Inja kohne hora...)
(Inja kohne stes...)
(Inja kohne era...)
(Inja kohne ntas...) [とある竜の恋の歌 / 作詞・作曲：江幡育子]
(Inja kohne ntas...) [A Certain Dragon's Love Song]
(Inja kohne som...)
(Inja kohne part...)
おどろの 大地に
Upon the thorny earth
恋の歌 響けば
Once the song of love resounds...
狂い出す 歯車
...the gears start running amok
止められぬ 定めが
And an unstoppable destiny...
弾けたように 蘇る
...springs back to life as if bursting open
今――
Now—
古より 寂寞の
Since ancient times, the desolate...
恋 目覚めた
...love has awakened
絆を求め 炎を 吐き散らす
Seeking our bond, breathing out flames
破壊と 再生
Destruction and rebirth
気高き 君の呪縛
The spell of you, the noble one
(Inja kohne ba...)
(Inja kohne hora...)
(Inja kohne stes...)
(Inja kohne era...)
(Inja kohne ntas...)
(Inja kohne som...)
(Inja kohne part...)
(Inja kohne kasa...)
(Inja kohne ano...)
透き通る 魂
A transparent soul
嘘もなく 気高く
Honestly and nobly
原罪を 抱えて
Carrying original sin
未熟な 恋求む
...seeking an immature love
愚かさ――
How foolish—
月明かり 今
The moonlight now...
二人 照らす
...shines upon the two
刹那の 時 重ねた
Layering moments of an instant
絆の 行方を
The whereabouts of our bond...
両手で 抱きしめた
...I embraced with both hands
終わりと 始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き 君の記憶
The precious memories of you
(Inja kohne ba...)
(Inja kohne hora...)
(Inja kohne stes...)
(Inja kohne era...)
(Inja kohne ntas...)
(Inja kohne som...)
(Inja kohne part...)
絆を求めて
Seeking our bond,
炎を飛ばす
unleashing the flames.
碧い糸
The blue thread...
再臨 気高き君の呪縛
Reincarnation, your noble spell.
絆の行方を
The destination of our bond...
両手で抱きしめた
I embraced it with both hands.
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning...
尊き君の記憶
The precious memory of you.
カイネ／救済
[Title: Kaine / Salvation]
Solhalm falm ouir iem
Har charu log neisien
Ga galg tayful
Mal g fuy de asla teres por
Yor tunder har kener lek voli ya boyo
Migen dya kroken no hei kainer o kalar
Migen dya kroken no hei ya mu tei koli rental maira chu
Solhalm falm ouir iem
Har charu log neisien
Ga galg tayful
Mal g fuy de asla teres por
Yor tunder har kener lek voli ya boyo
Migen dya kroken no hei kainer o kalar
Migen dya kroken no hei ya mu tei koli rental maira chu
時の揺り籠で
In the cradle of time,
冷たい夢を見る
I dream a cold dream.
君が歌ってくれた
You sang to me...
優しい 優しい 子守唄
a sweet, sweet lullaby.
君が望んだのは
What you wished for was...
終わらぬ世界
...an endless world.
僕が望むのは
What I wish for is...
世界の終わり
...the end of the world.
選ばれし声を
With this chosen voice,
迷い 憂い 偽り 歌う
lost, grieving, deceiving, I sing.
悲しみは喜び 悲しみを笑顔に変えて
Turning sadness into joy, and sorrow into smiles.
報われずに
Without being rewarded,
君は朽ちていくの？
are you going to decay?
共に辿るこの世界 ただ君だけ
Walking this world together... but only with you,
想いは交わらない
our thoughts will never meet.
巡り巡る命の歌 世界に この手で
The repeating song of life... in this world, with these hands,
安らぎと祝福を
I want to bring peace and blessings...
終わらせたい
...I want to end it.
伝わらない 心の願いは
Our unreached wishes,
虚しさだけを残して
leaving behind only emptiness...
始まる
...begins.
(Ina) 嘆きの旋律 響き渡る 全てを忘れて / (Bae) 終わらぬ絶望 歌声を希望に変えて 叫び続ける
(Ina) The melody of grief resounds, forgetting everything / (Bae) Endless despair... turning my voice into hope, I keep screaming
(Ina) 巡る世界に 祈りを / (Bae) 抗う定めを 闇を暴いて
(Ina) Releasing my prayers into the spinning world / (Bae) Exposing the darkness of this resisting fate,
今 解き放つ
we unleash it now.
君が望んだのは
What you wished for was...
あなたの未来
...your future.
僕が望んだのは
What I wished for was...
戻らぬ日々を 祈り続けたのは
...to keep praying for days that won't return.
優しい 笑顔 それだけなのに 終わらない
Only a gentle smile, and yet... it never ends.
(Bae) 絶望の歌声を 希望に変えて / (Ina) 叫び続けよう
(Bae) Turning this song of despair into hope / (Ina) Let's keep screaming...
抗う定めなら
If it's a fate we must resist,
慈しんで
...cherish it.
冷たい記憶を 僕らの歌よ 響け
Cold memories... May our song resound!
巡り巡る世界に 安らぎと祝福を
In the spinning world, peace and blessings...
奏でよう 光を 定めを
...let's play. Light... Fate...
闇を 暴いて 今解き放つ
Exposing the darkness, we unleash it now!
(Bae) 絶望の歌声を 希望に変えて / (Ina) 叫び続けたら
(Bae) Turning this song of despair into hope / (Ina) If we keep screaming...
(Bae) 君は朽ちていくの？ / (Ina) 愛しき日々
(Bae) ...will you decay? / (Ina) Beloved days...
冷たい記憶を 僕らの歌よ 響け
Cold memories... May our song resound!
君が望んだのは
What you wished for was...
僕が望んだのは
...what I wished for was...
残された声は 嘆き 君を想いながら
The remaining voice is grieving, while thinking of you,
一人 君のために歌う
...singing all alone for you.
一人 君のために
All alone, for you...
巡り巡る 命の歌 世界に
The repeating song of life, in this world...
(Ina) 安らぎと祝福を / (Bae) 終わらせたい
(Ina) ...peace and blessings / (Bae) I want to end it
定めに抗って行く この身は 君とならどこまででも
We will fight against fate... with this body, if it's with you, I'll go anywhere.
(Ina) 嘆きの旋律 響き渡る 全てを忘れて / (Bae) 終わらぬ絶望 歌声を希望に変えて 叫び続ける
(Ina) The melody of grief resounds, forgetting everything / (Bae) Endless despair... turning my voice into hope, I keep screaming
(Ina) 巡る世界に 祈りを / (Bae) 抗う定めを 闇を暴いて
(Ina) Releasing my prayers into the spinning world / (Bae) Exposing the darkness of this resisting fate,
今 解き放つ
we unleash it now.
光の底に
At the bottom of the light,
眠れ
...sleep.
Bae, are you okay?
Oh! My knight!
Finally you have come!
Seriously, I've waited like a hundred years, mate. What took you so long?
A hundred... hundred years?
Wait, hold on, hold on.
How... Google, how long does a rat live?
Man, all of... all of my muscles...
...they are so rigid from being stuck as a statue, but thank you so much for saving me.
Don't worry. You know what? Ina-nis the hero is here to save you.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah, we defeated the evil... witch!
Witch again?
Serves them right!
I don't know if you saw, but there was an evil dragon.
Yeah! How dare they!
Are you okay? Are you all good?
I'm good. Everything is good. Thank you.
Now that you're all well, you might as well...
...say the thing.
Say the thing, you know, the thing.
What thing?
You know, like today is a special day.
Oh! Yeah, today is...
Today is the day that...
...the princess has been saved!
Thank you very much! Thank you!
拍手、拍手、はい！ あざます、あざます！
Clap, clap, yes! Thank you, thank you!
No, no, no, Bae, Bae, Bae.
What day is...
...when this purple one become to be?
...when this purple one became to be?
Oh! I see! You're looking for that one!
Yeah, yeah, okay, okay.
Ina-chan, Happy Birthday!
Yay! Thanks for joining me today, Bae!
Thanks for inviting me! It was so much fun!
It was so fun!
Yeah, to dance with you, sing with you, is the best.
I just wanted to say, your new outfit is so cute!
Thank you! You like it?
It's so cute! Oh my god!
It's called...
What's the outfit called?
勇者！
Yusha!
That's right, I look like a hero, right?
You do look like a hero.
My hero.
Aw, Bae!
And Mr. Squeaks, thanks for leading me to Bae!
Thanks, man, you did great!
High five! High five!
If it wasn't for him, I'd be stuck as a statue forever.
Don't shake your head too much, it's going to fall off.
Yes, yes, too late for that.
But yeah, thank you, Bae, for saving me.
Are you still continuing your journey after this?
I am a hero, after all. I gotta go see all the princesses...
...I gotta save.
Excuse me? It wasn't just me?
All right, let's go! Bye!
Well, that's that.
On to the next princess, let's go!
Many days ended in fairy tales
Departure arrived at the end, group we have seen
I recall, parts of our trip so long, a passage of time
The robust and brave hero of this land
Shadows of nightmare manifested, then no more
There was a hero who took on all foes
Our short journey, memory with you
No more pages left in that story
Our hero goes into slumber deep
Leaving behind a veil of peace for all
Saving the world we once knew
The flow of time erased without mercy
Any traces of memories and youth
Even the traces left in life for now
Rusting as time issues
And yet, I keep all your hopes
All the words and wishes, courage you won
They'll dwell inside me, and even now, in my heart
Keep living through
On a very same path, nothing more to do
Our trip should have ended, but suddenly I was wondering
All those tears flowing down my cheeks
Why do they come out and fall?
I wanna find out, and surely we will right now
If I engage in the journey we might learn about you again
Though I am no longer walking next to you
One day I know I'll find the truth
Rays of light, impact of a new story
On to the path, before this journey's story
I'll keep this recalled forever, ever, ever, I know
Another story untold
Into a journey that alone I set out to
I meet the locals of every town I stop in
They are all recalling the person that you were
Unwavering kindness is spoken of you
A thing not cooling, everything you do
Here and there, we can find scatters of symbols around
Manifesting that all will prove peace
And even that was because of you
So one day I would not find myself all alone, becoming lonely
And I recall to mind every moment of our journey
When I see the signs left in these scenes
Many days ended in fairy tales
Departure arrived at the end, group we have seen
And it was that moment our history started for me
Even if your courage is what proved to be the best, yes
And I will make sure it's what everybody can recall
I will bring you along with me into the future's light
Just like, taking your hand in mine
And so it all began right at that time
One day in everyday life, some moment ignite
Leaving a lot of with you, remaining my reflections of those times
Go on as brightly shining scenes
I wanna find out, and surely we will right now
Looking back at you standing, taking a step proud forever
...staring right at me without a sound
I'm perceiving you around
But this journey's story
will be the end of the hero
forever, ever, ever after, you know
Now, the beginning has began to be an end
and the state that you protect and care has been safely...
These budding lives are with me on this journey
Yay!
And then they lived happily ever after.
Or should I say... evermore?
Well, yeah. Thank you guys for watching today!
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Make sure you, you know, tell me how it was using the hashtag.
And of course, since it is my birthday,
I also have to introduce some of my birthday merch to you guys! Yay!
So we have these items for...
um, the birthday merch this year. Let's see.
Ta-dan!
Yay! Look, this is my 2025 birthday merch.
Uh, we have a couple of items. So the first item...
Next!
Okay, with the first item, we have the Reversible Tote Bag.
It has a different design on each side.
So depending on what you feel like having on the outside,
you can choose between the lovely, lovely key visual by chibi-sensei,
or a very simplified design to be more incognito.
And of course, we have another one. So, next!
We have the Takogame! Shaker Acrylic Keychain.
This one, I designed myself.
And I wanted to be kind of like, you know, you can carry it around
and it kind of seems like a little game that you can play.
You can shake it around and the Takodachis will shake. It's a really fun item.
And then...
next, we also have
the Takodachi Cable Tie,
where you can organize the messy, messy chaos that is...
the cables in your bag, like, like me.
But yeah, I hope they're useful.
And last but not least, we have the... next!
Yuusha Ina, aka...
Ninomae Ina'nis the Hero.
This outfit! I call myself the hero.
It's a clear, cute plushie keychain
that you can carry around everywhere, and I will protect you. It's a lucky charm.
But yeah.
And of course, there is a full set bonus
which is going to be a limited, or, I will have a limited edition
postcard.
But if you buy the set, you also get the postcard. There's a limited set and a not limited set, so
there's that.
And of course, we also have a special Hololive
TCG card with the key art.
It's like a thank you bonus for the complete set of the merch.
Um, you know, this card will only be given to customers who purchase the Hololive Production... oh,
purchased from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
And this is a Oshi Holomem card
which you can use, only one in the game.
I know there's a whole bunch of rules that you can check out on the website.
Unfortunately, it's only the Japanese version, there's only Japanese text on it,
but, you know, it's kind of like a special limited thing, so
something nice to have.
But yeah, that is it for...
merch announcement, etc.
I hope you guys enjoyed the live today.
And of course, we still have the omake, the little ending,
kind of, snippets in the end, and the credits, so
please look forward to that.
Until next time, thank you again everyone!
Have a wonderful rest of the morning, afternoon, evening.
I'll see you guys later.
Bye-bye!
Thanks for watching, everyone!!! I'm really happy that I was able to share this special day with you today!
Did you enjoy the live? Do you like the new outfit?? Hehe.
Just like the theme of the outfit, I would like to continue to do my bestest with everything I do!
Because that is what a hero... yuusha would do! Thank you for cheering for me! Always!!
I really wouldn't be here without all your support!! And of course, BIG thank you to all the staff & creators that could make this happen too!!
I am always indebted to everyone's passion! THANK YOU, THANK YOU, & THANK YOU!! It's time... TO GO NEXT!!